const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",i="insurance",o=200,t=120,a=[{id:164,question:"Change for the transportation of goods by water is called",option:{a:"Bill",b:"Ticket",c:"Freight",d:"Consideration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:8,question:"The evidence of the insurance contract is",option:{a:"proposal form",b:"policy",c:"schedule",d:"endorsement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:169,question:"A customer that suffers loss or sustain injury while using a business outfit that belongs to another perosn, can sue the property owner under -------------- insurance",option:{a:"Professional indemnity",b:"Public liability",c:"Employers’ liability",d:"Personal accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:181,question:"To break or act contrary to a law or promise means",option:{a:"Breach",b:"Shake",c:"Confirm",d:"Disagreement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:232,question:"When the proposer fails to fill the proposal form truthfully, the contract will become",option:{a:"voidable",b:"illegal",c:"void",d:"enforceable"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:154,question:"---------- is the evidence cover of the risk given to the insured by the insurer",option:{a:"Cover",b:"Policy",c:"Claim",d:"Compensation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:318,question:"The policy that covers  an  insured  employee  against injury  sustained  in  the  course  of  employment  is",option:{a:"professional indemnity",b:"product liability",c:"public liability",d:"employer’s liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:330,question:"The amount payable to an insured in the event of fire damage of household items is the",option:{a:"cost of repair",b:"actual cash value",c:"replacement cost",d:"sum insured"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:156,question:"A temporary certificate to show that a cover is in existence is called",option:{a:"Policy",b:"Certificate",c:"Cover note",d:"Claim slip"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:109,question:"In the utmost good faith principle, the value of the subject matter should",option:{a:"Be over stated",b:"Understated",c:"Not be stated",d:"Not be overstated nor understated"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:278,question:"Physical loss of limbs or total blindness injury is an example of",option:{a:"permanent disablement",b:"temporary disablement",c:"mid-term disablement",d:"total disablement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:123,question:"Risk whose cause is beyond human control is",option:{a:"Fundamental",b:"Speculative",c:"Particular",d:"Static"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:33,question:"George effected two personal accident policies. The first policy provides N= 25,000.00 cover for loss of limb. The second policy provides N= 30,000.00 cover for loss of limb. What is the total amount that  George  will receive in the event of a valid loss of limb claim?",option:{a:"N= 5,000.00",b:"N= 25,000.00",c:"N= 30,000.00",d:"N= 55,000.00"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:235,question:"Proposal form is not applicable to the following except",option:{a:"aviation",b:"engineering",c:"large risk of fire",d:"fidelity guarantee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:312,question:"In a life assurance contract, when does  the  principle of insurable interest arise?",option:{a:"At the beginning of the contract",b:"At the time of claim",c:"At the middle of the contract",d:"At the time of payment of premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:40,question:"The owner of a life assurance policy who enters into an agreement to sell the ownership of the policy and beneficiary rights upon the death of the insured is called",option:{a:"an underwriter",b:"a aviator",c:"a factor",d:"an assessor"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:69,question:"The seller of insurance product is",option:{a:"Insurer",b:"Insured",c:"Broker",d:"Agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:113,question:"A peril is best defined as",option:{a:"Chance of a loss",b:"The occurrence of a loan",c:"The cause of a loss",d:"The result of a loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:61,question:"The payment made by the insured to the insurer upon which the validity of insurance is based is called",option:{a:"Exgratia payment",b:"Loss payment",c:"Compensation",d:"Premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:288,question:"Marine  losses are divided into",option:{a:"actual total and total loss",b:"total loss and partial loss",c:"partial loss and actual loss",d:"average loss and partial loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:269,question:"To which of the following does the principle of utmost good faith apply in a contract of insurance?",option:{a:"the insurer only",b:"the proposer only",c:"the third party and insured",d:"insurer and proposer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:150,question:"The legal right to insure a subject matter is",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Subject Matter",c:"Subrogation",d:"Insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:79,question:"Hazard that relates to the attitude of the insured is known as",option:{a:"Physical hazard",b:"Good physical hazard",c:"Moral hazard",d:"Good moral hazard"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:307,question:"A fire insurance policy guaranteed by the insured to be in place for a stated period with a particular insurer is granted a _____________",option:{a:"no claim discount",b:"fleet discount",c:"long - term agreement discount",d:"plurality discount"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:332,question:"One of the benefits payable under personal accident insurance policy is",option:{a:"retirement benefit",b:"surrender benefit",c:"death benefit",d:"transfer benefit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:335,question:"Who  among  the  following  is  an  employer  of  loss adjuster?",option:{a:"Insurer",b:"Broker",c:"Insured",d:"Agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:218,question:"Non- indemnity insurance means that the assured can",option:{a:"be restored back to his former position",b:"not be restored back to his former position",c:"be brought back to contract",d:"not be brought back to contract"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:241,question:"Policy condition which are automatically applicable and not stated in the contract of agreement is known as",option:{a:"agreed condition",b:"agreed negotiation",c:"implied condition",d:"expressed condition"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:1,question:"Which of the following policies will prevent loss of home if the wage earner dies?",option:{a:"Term assurance",b:"Endowment assurance",c:"Mortgage insurance",d:"Whole life assurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:289,question:"The division of total loss are",option:{a:"average loss and partial loss",b:"partial loss and full loss",c:"total loss and actual loss",d:"actual total loss and constructive total loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:194,question:"A particular risk which is transferred to another re-insurance under a re-insurance treaty is",option:{a:"Cedant",b:"Cession",c:"Facultative",d:"Cede"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:134,question:"A house worth N=60,000 insured against fire for N=40,000.  Fire destroyed and cause damage worth N=30,000. On the house under which insurance principle will the owner be entitled to compensation of N=30,000.",option:{a:"Contribution",b:"Subrogation",c:"indemnity",d:"Uberrimae fidei"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:178,question:"Indemnity is provided through the following media except",option:{a:"Cash",b:"Commission",c:"Reinstatement",d:"Repair"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:216,question:"With assurance contract there is",option:{a:"uncertainly of reward",b:"certainty of reward",c:"certainty of occurrence",d:"uncertainty of occurrence"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:184,question:"The principle that requires all material facts to be disclosed is known as",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Fidelity",c:"Proximate cause",d:"Utmost good faith"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:14,question:"Abandonment is mostly applicable to",option:{a:"marine insurance",b:"motor insurance",c:"fire insurance",d:"engineering insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:146,question:"Workman compensation is also referred to as",option:{a:"Fidelity insurance",b:"Employment liability",c:"Public liability",d:"Product liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:81,question:"The following are examples of bad moral hazard except",option:{a:"Fraudulent activities",b:"Carelessness",c:"Honesty",d:"Unreasonableness"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:303,question:"Which of the following is a component of premium in insurance?",option:{a:"Margin",b:"Reserve",c:"Funds",d:"Capital"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:25,question:"A method of providing indemnity in the event of loss is",option:{a:"cash payment",b:"professional advice",c:"resolution of dispute",d:"resolution of policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:117,question:"There must  be  a  close  connection  between  the loss actually suffered and the risk is relating to the principle  of",option:{a:"Abandonment",b:"Proximate cause",c:"Utmost good faith",d:"Adhesion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:326,question:"What is the full meaning of “NCRIB” in the insurance industry?",option:{a:"National  Council of  Registered Insurance  Brokers",b:"Nigerian  Council of  Registered Insurance  Brokers",c:"Nigerian Corporation of Registered Insurance Brokers",d:"National Corporation of Registered Insurance Brokers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:72,question:"The risks which affect the society and whose causes are beyond human control is",option:{a:"particular risk",b:"static",c:"fundamental",d:"speculative"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:82,question:"The cause of a loss is known as",option:{a:"Risk",b:"Peril",c:"Hazard",d:"Moral"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:121,question:"Insurance is necessary because of the need to",option:{a:"Pool resources together",b:"Meet uncertainties in future",c:"Make profit",d:"Lend money to individual"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:58,question:"In insurance contract the insured is the",option:{a:"offeror",b:"offeree",c:"Actuary",d:"Ofree"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:268,question:"The payment made when the insured is not entitled to claim under a policy is",option:{a:"voluntary excess",b:"ex-gratia",c:"return premium",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:338,question:"The amount charged when a ship overstays at the port under a marine contract is",option:{a:"penalty",b:"fine",c:"overcharge",d:"demurrage"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:94,question:"Payment of claims  in  liability  insurance are usually made in favour of",option:{a:"insurance agent",b:"a third party",c:"employees",d:"employers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:246,question:"One of these is a form of motor vehicle insurance policy",option:{a:"comprehensive",b:"1st party only",c:"2nd party only",d:"accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:45,question:"The consideration paid for insurance contract is",option:{a:"money",b:"commission",c:"premium",d:"fee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:277,question:"policy designed for the insured who is incapacitated to carry out normal duty is",option:{a:"medical expenses",b:"temporary disablement",c:"permanent disablement",d:"medical expenses"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:139,question:"Consequential loss is also known as",option:{a:"Business interruption insurance",b:"Credit insurance",c:"Excess loss",d:"Property insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:32,question:"A contract sold  by  insurance companies that  pay  a monthly or  quarterly income  benefit for the  life  of a person is",option:{a:"endowment",b:"annuity",c:"income",d:"freight"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:300,question:"One of these is a full time professional",option:{a:"broker",b:"agent",c:"factor",d:"insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:64,question:"Which of these is an aid to trade?",option:{a:"cover note",b:"insurance",c:"premium",d:"policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:85,question:"Transfer of rights and liabilities under a contract with the consent of the other party is known as",option:{a:"Assignment",b:"liability",c:"Interest",d:"Legality"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:328,question:"The cover that is taken at the option of the motor vehicle owner is",option:{a:"a comprehensive cover",b:"an act only cover",c:"a third party only cover",d:"a special type cover"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:110,question:"Which of the following is non- insurable risk?",option:{a:"Gambling",b:"Accident",c:"Fire",d:"Theft"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:302,question:"Which  of  the  following  is  not  a  component  of  an insurance policy?",option:{a:"Signature clause",b:"Particular clause",c:"Recital clause",d:"Operative clause"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:188,question:"Method of providing indemnity whereby subject matter is being restored to its former position is",option:{a:"Repairs",b:"Cash",c:"Reinstatement",d:"Replacement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:18,question:"How  much  premium  will  the  insurer  return  to  the insured?",option:{a:"N= 3,750",b:"N= 13,750",c:"N= 17,500",d:"N= 31,250"},section:"XYC Industries Limited proposed a fire risk to Adequate Insurance Plc. on a total sum insured of N= 5,000,000.00. The risk was accepted on a premium rate of 0.35%. After survey, the insurer charged a rate of 0.275%.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:238,question:"Situation that are not included in the policy are usually referred to as",option:{a:"condition",b:"exception",c:"preamble",d:"operative clause"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:102,question:"Insurable interest means",option:{a:"Interest gained on money in a bank",b:"Interest payable on a loan",c:"Financial interest a person has in something he expects to inherit",d:"The financial interest a person has in something of value"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:293,question:"The form of risk that can easily be calculated and estimated is known as",option:{a:"non insurable risk",b:"non-financial risk",c:"speculative risk",d:"insurable risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:243,question:"The process of changing what is wrong in the policy is called",option:{a:"specification",b:"attestation clause",c:"rectification",d:"justification"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:166,question:"Another name for consequential loss is",option:{a:"Stop loss",b:"Credit insurance",c:"Business interruption insurance",d:"Excess loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:262,question:"One of this is a method of claim settlement",option:{a:"price",b:"trade by barter",c:"exchange",d:"cash"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:56,question:"A fundamental condition which must be filled  by the  insured for compensation is",option:{a:"warranty",b:"obligation",c:"interest",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:306,question:"Which of the following is the function of a loss adjuster?",option:{a:"Ensures payment of adequate compensation",b:"Advises the insurer on claim",c:"Operates with unlimited authority",d:"Notifies insurer of the loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:55,question:"A  statement  of  fact  that  the insured must have an interest in the object of the contract is called",option:{a:"warranty",b:"insurable interest",c:"subrogation",d:"object interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:267,question:"One of this is the consideration paid for insurance contract",option:{a:"fee",b:"cheque",c:"commission",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:224,question:"Risk that affect the society and whose causes are beyond human control is",option:{a:"particular risk",b:"pure risk",c:"fundamental risk",d:"static risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:107,question:"Insurance was developed as a result of the existence of",option:{a:"Hazards",b:"Loss",c:"Risk",d:"Indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:209,question:"In insurance, uncertainty of loss means",option:{a:"hazard",b:"risk",c:"accident",d:"earthquake"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:294,question:"A risk that has its origin in the activities of an individual and the effects borne by this individual is called",option:{a:"pure risk",b:"particular risk",c:"speculative risk",d:"fundamental risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:324,question:"Insurance is described as a risk",option:{a:"avoidance mechanism",b:"regulating mechanism",c:"transfer mechanism",d:"assessment mechanism"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:16,question:"In the preparation of food for eat - in - customers, the cooks made a mistake in using excess quantity of an 	ingredient. A customer ate and  suffered  poisoning. 	Which policy of the operator would pick this liability?",option:{a:"Public liability",b:"Personal liability",c:"All risks insurance",d:"Loss of profit insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:348,question:"The principle of maritime law which makes owners of a ship and cargo share in a loss incurred voluntarily is",option:{a:"special average",b:"general average",c:"specific average",d:"particular average"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:101,question:"When someone is placed back in the same financial position that he was in just prior to a loss, that is ----",option:{a:"Actual cash value",b:"Consideration",c:"Contribution",d:"Indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:334,question:"The process of  assessing  risks  in  insurance  and classifying them according to their degree of insurability so  that  the  appropriate  rate  may  be  assigned  is",option:{a:"inspecting",b:"underwriting",c:"surveying",d:"evaluating"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:331,question:"A motorist travelling from Ghana to Nigeria would be required to obtain one of the following types of motor insurance cover",option:{a:"green card",b:"brown card",c:"yellow card",d:"purple card"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:106,question:"The amount of money paid periodically by an insured to the insurance company to cover risk is called",option:{a:"Commission",b:"Premium",c:"Cover note",d:"Dividend"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:292,question:"Speailative risks are",option:{a:"insurable risk",b:"non insurable risk",c:"financial risk",d:"non financial risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:231,question:"The statement “ I to the best of my knowledge hereby confirm that the statements contained in this prosal form are true and correct” represents",option:{a:"confirmation",b:"declaration",c:"witnessing",d:"humility"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:337,question:"The  document issued by  the  insurer when there is a change in the particulars of a risk insured is",option:{a:"endorsement",b:"certificate",c:"voucher",d:"policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:103,question:"Below are insurable policies except",option:{a:"Earthquake",b:"Fire",c:"Life",d:"Marine"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:37,question:"Which  of the following activities is  not a  function of the  Chartered  Insurance  Institute  of  Nigeria?",option:{a:"Setting a standard for members",b:"Promoting Professional growth",c:"Promoting the interest of insurers",d:"Specifying professional qualification"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:120,question:"An application form which is filled by anyone taking out an insurance policy is called",option:{a:"A policy form",b:"A claim form",c:"A proposal form",d:"Proximate cause form"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:39,question:"The payment made when the insured is  not  entitled to claim under a policy is",option:{a:"voluntary excess",b:"ex-gratia",c:"return premium",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:147,question:"An insurance cover for lawyers, accountants and brokers is",option:{a:"Employment",b:"Professional",c:"Public",d:"Product"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:229,question:"One of the following is a condition for contribution",option:{a:"bilateral interest",b:"multilatual interest",c:"two subject matter",d:"common subject matter"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:290,question:"Marine insurance policy which covers all the ship or vessels belonging to one owner is",option:{a:"flect policy",b:"mixed policy",c:"value policy",d:"fixed policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:126,question:"Uncertainty of loss is known as",option:{a:"Risk",b:"Certainty",c:"Insurance",d:"Hazard"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:88,question:"A miss statement of fact that is made by the insured or his broker to an underwriter during negotiation is called",option:{a:"annuity",b:"misrepresentation",c:"endorsement",d:"disclosure"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:343,question:"Which of the following activities is not involved in claims management?",option:{a:"Proof of loss",b:"Particulars of loss",c:"Premium calculation",d:"Primary investigation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:112,question:"Hazard that deals with the human habits and character that arises from human attitude and the conduct of people is called",option:{a:"physical",b:"Moral",c:"Static",d:"Dynamic"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:83,question:"The  principle  of  insurance  which  states  that a person must be in a legally recognized relationship to what is  insured  such  that  he  will  benefit  from its existence or suffer by its loss is",option:{a:"utmost good faith",b:"insurable interest",c:"proximate cause",d:"subrogation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:273,question:"A residential building built beside a petrol filling station is described as a",option:{a:"risk",b:"hazard",c:"peril",d:"liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:36,question:"The professional service required for effective claims administration by insurers would be provided by",option:{a:"loss assessors",b:"risk managers",c:"loss adjusters",d:"claims consultants"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:68,question:"The buyer of insurance product is",option:{a:"Agent",b:"Broker",c:"Insured",d:"Insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:346,question:"The saving element in a permanent life assurance policy which represent the policyholder’s interest in the policy is",option:{a:"surrender value",b:"cash value",c:"sum assured",d:"residual value"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:260,question:"If the insured has been fully indemnified, the insurers are entitled to take any advantage due to the insured. Principle of insurance involved is",option:{a:"insurable interest",b:"contribution",c:"indemnity",d:"subrogation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:93,question:"Subrogation principle can be applied in the following insurance policies except in",option:{a:"aviation policy",b:"engineering policy",c:"life policy",d:"marine policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:91,question:"A financial compensation sufficient to return the insured back to the original position after loss is known as",option:{a:"deposit",b:"loan",c:"indemnity",d:"profit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:138,question:"The duty of the loss adjuster in insurance claims is to",option:{a:"Make loss",b:"Prevent loss",c:"Safeguard loss",d:"Recommend appropriate payment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:115,question:"Insurance  feature  that  emphasized   the  fact  that insurance contract is a contract between the insurer and  the  insured  and  which states  that  the insured must  adhere to  the  agreement  is  called",option:{a:"Disclosure",b:"Warranty",c:"Adhesion",d:"Material facts"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:133,question:"When an insured person admits that he has indemnified, he means that",option:{a:"The damage proper by has been recovered",b:"He was paid premium fully",c:"The insurance company has restored him to his former position",d:"He was paid his premium fully"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:329,question:"The  sum  insured  for  a  risk  is  N= 150,000  and  was accepted  for  fire  insurance at a rate of  0.25%. How much will the insured pay as a premium?",option:{a:"N= 125",b:"N= 375",c:"N= 500",d:"N= 875"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:265,question:"Which of the following risks is covered by insurance policy?",option:{a:"an investment loss on the stock market",b:"dishonesty of an employee leading to fraud",c:"failure of a business venture",d:"rise and fall of prices of goods in the market"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:272,question:"A factor which may influence the occurrence of a loss is",option:{a:"peril",b:"loss",c:"hazard",d:"risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:252,question:"Subrogation in insurance means that",option:{a:"the insured could not make a profit from the insurer",b:"the insured must be fully indemnified",c:"the insurer must take the place of the insured",d:"the insured should pool their risks"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:29,question:"A provision in a policy that exempts an insurer from liability if the loss is less than a certain amount is",option:{a:"excess",b:"transfer",c:"lay days",d:"franchise"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:158,question:"The cause of a loss is known as",option:{a:"Peril",b:"Hazard",c:"Loss",d:"Risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:129,question:"The  payment  made  by  underwriter  as  a  form  of  	kindness  without  admission  of  liability  so  as  to maintain goodwill is known as ------------",option:{a:"Kindness payment",b:"Ex-gratia payment",c:"Favour payment",d:"Claim"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:286,question:"The amount given to the insured if he does not want the contract to continue is called",option:{a:"premium",b:"price",c:"consideration",d:"surrender value"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:162,question:"The essential value of valid contract that states that the parties to a contract must be in perfect agreement and have a common mind is",option:{a:"Consideration",b:"Perpetual existence",c:"Excess",d:"Consensus ad-idem"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:108,question:"Which of the following is not a function of insurance?",option:{a:"Serves as collateral",b:"Encouraging saving",c:"Provides insecurity",d:"Reduces risks"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:144,question:"The date on which an insurance or reinsurance contract comes into force is known as",option:{a:"Starting point date",b:"Inception date",c:"Beginning date",d:"Commencement date"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:253,question:"Payment by the insurer to the insured out of sympathy is known as",option:{a:"utmost good faith",b:"proximate cause",c:"peril",d:"ex-gratia payment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"}],n={message:e,subject:i,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,n as default,e as message,o as status,i as subject,t as total};
